Guide to The Richard Hess Mullin-Palmer Tape Restoration Project Collection ARS.0035
Archive of Recorded Sound
Richard Hess Mullin-Palmer Tape Restoration Project Collection
1934-2008
Bulk, 1946-1950
ARS.0035
Hess, Richard L.
6 linear feet: 110 digital files; 54 open reel tapes
Six boxes of audiotape are held by the Archive of Recorded Sound. The remainder of the collection is digital.
Archive of Recorded Sound
Tapes and digitally transferred files from the early years of American tape recording. Transfers were done by engineer and researcher Richard L. Hess. Digital files are only available at Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Historical Background
The Richard Hess Mullin-Palmer Tape Restoration Project Collection chronicles the widespread dissemination of one of the most important advances in sound recording technology: magnetic recording on tape. In 1945, a U.S. Army Signal Corp soldier named John T. "Jack" Mullin was assigned to recover examples of the latest German technology from the field. In a radio station, Mullin confirmed that the Germans had developed a system of sound recording and reproduction using paper and plastic tape. He returned to the United States with several reels of audio tape and two AEG Magnetophon brand reel-to-reel machines on which to play them. This was not the first time that this country was introduced to the technology (in fact, research was published widely in the 30s), but Mullin's initiative, along with the enterprise of filmmaker Bill Palmer, was essentially the avenue by which tape manufacturing began in the United States.
The story of Bing Crosby's involvement is familiar. In the late 1940s, Crosby hosted one of the most popular programs on radio: Philco Radio Time. Mullin and Palmer approached Crosby with their idea, and a company named Ampex, with backing from Crosby, developed its first model of tape recorder, the 200, in 1947 (other companies, among them Brush, Rangertone, Orradio, and Presto, were also experimenting with magnetic recording with some success). Tape provided an ease of editing that appealed to Crosby and his producers, and allowed for more creativity in assembling programs. It was also thought to offer improved fidelity. Because of the risk of tape failing during a live broadcast, shows were still aired from transcription discs; it was the recording and editing that was done with tape. The first program recorded on tape was broadcast October 1st, 1947, the start of the 1947-1948 season. The recordings in this collection consist largely of material used for the Philco program, including performances, outtakes, and advertisements. Among the other stars to be heard on the programs are Dinah Shore, Peggy Lee, Burl Ives, and Claudette Colbert.
The Richard Hess Collection is named for recording historian and audio engineer Richard L. Hess who assembled these tapes, transferred them, and provided detailed notes on both the content and its capture. Between 2001 and 2008, Hess drew from both public and private collections to construct a digital representation of the early days of magnetic recording in the United States.
Scope and Contents
A significant portion of this collection (Reels 1-51) are reels of audio tape which are physically held at the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound. However, the bulk of the collection consists of digital files, including transfers from those reels, as well as from tapes in several other collections not at Stanford. Prior to accession, each item (whether a physical reel or the digital file that was recorded from the tape) was assigned a reel number. There is also a series for all related documentation, including obituaries and tape transfer logs.
Arrangement
This collection is divided into five series. The first four are grouped according to their original donor, and Series 5 assembles most of the textual information concerning the collection.
Related Collections
Stanford also holds the Ampex Corporation Collection. Some material presented here is also available through the Pavek Museum of Broadcasting.
Indexing Terms
Allgemeine Elektricitats-Gesellschaft (Germany).; Ampex Corporation.; Collier, Eve Mullin; Crosby, Bing, 1903-1977; Mullin, John T. (Jack), 1913-1999; Ososke, Don; Palmer, William A., 1911-1996; Pavek Museum of Broadcasting.; Audiotapes; Magnetic tape industry; Radio programs
- Series 1. Jack Mullin-Bill Palmer, 6 boxes: 4 boxes of 54 open reel tapes, 2 boxes of tape parts, approx. 50 sound files; This is the only series in which the content's physical carriers and containers (tape, reels and packaging) are held in addition to the content's digital transfers.
  Source of Acquisition
  Jack Mullin and Bill Palmer Agfa 1943 tapes temporarily owned by former Ampex employee Jim Wheeler. Wheeler arranged for their donation to the Archive of Recorded Sound. Content was transferred in 2003.
  - Reels 1-51
    - Reel 1, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_01.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 4, Reel 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Bing Crosby (possibly from ET); John Scott Trotter "You Tell Me Your Dream"; "Haunted Heart" from Inside USA; "Haunted Heart" from Inside USA; "Love is so Terrific"; "Love is So Terrific" (with noticeable splice in the middle); "Blue Shadows on the Trail" from Disney movie Melody Time (Crosby makes a wisecrack during a false start); "Jeepers Creepers"; "I Only have Eyes for You" (take 1, incomplete); "I Only have Eyes for You" (take 2, incomplete)
      Format
      Audio tape, Digital .wav audio file
    - Reel 2, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_02.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 4, Reel 2)
      Bing Crosby "La Vie en Rose" (take 1); "La Vie en Rose" (take 1); "La Vie en Rose" (take 2); "I May Be Wrong"; "I Think You're Marvelous" (take 1); "I May Be Wrong" (take 2); "I May Be Wrong" (take 3); Modernaires? "Thousand Islands"; Modernaires? "Thousand Islands" (take 2); "Thousand Islands" (take 3); yodeling; "Let the Song Begin" from the movie Emperor Waltz
      Audiotape, Digital .wav audio file
    - Reel 3, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_03.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 4, Reel 3)
      band, classical; Bing Crosby excerpts; female singer "Trouble is a Man"
    - Reel 4, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_04.wav ), 1948-12; 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 4)
      Burl Ives "Twelve days of Christmas"; spliced up Corinna Mura outtakes (first and last backward); Philco 1948 commercial; next week: Marais and Miranda; Christmas Seals
    - Reel 5, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_05.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 4, Reel 5)
      orchestra (distorted, disc recording?) mostly blank. "PARIS" written on the IEC hub
    - Reel 6, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_06.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 4, Reel 6)
      probably a talk given at the Bohemian Club (Palmer was active member). Note attached to tape: "#2 Al Gordon-China"
    - Reel 7, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_07.wav ), 1948; 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 4, Reel 7)
      Philco Radio Show 1948; Burl Ives - "Mr. Froggy" (take 1); "On Top of Old Smokey"; Dinah Shore; Burl Ives, Dinah Shore "Cockle Shells" (end of take 1, start of take 2); "Mr. Froggy"
    - Reel 8, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_08.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 2, Reel 8)
      Bing Crosby "Story of Sorrento" (start); reversed section; outtakes reel; cowboy song outtake; "Pop goes the weasel"; Foley practice; Bill Palmer voice "Recording, but not doing well"; last half silence with hundreds of splices
    - Reel 9, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_09.wav ), 1950; 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 2, Reel 9)
      highly edited Pacific Gas and Electric spot; 1950 Rainier Beer Commercial (5 takes)
    - Reel 10, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_10.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 4, Reel 10)
      folk dancing in California; announcements; music
    - Reel 11, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_11.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 4, Reel 11)
      Del Monte script repeated many times (only partially recorded)
    - Reel 12, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_12.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 4, Reel 12)
      34:00 backwards (now corrected)
    - Reel 13, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_13.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 4, Reel 13)
      high level distorted music; "Merry Widow" excerpt (from disc); Bill Palmer and buddies "Down by the Old Mill Stream" excerpt. "Tests of RPF in Paris" written on hub
    - Reel 14, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_14.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 2, Reel 14)
      Acme Beer dialogue; Joe Baldwin Show; KSFO San Francisco excerpts; John Nesbitt Passing Parade; Mutual Broadcasting System; "A Killer Named Accident" National Safety Council PSA
    - Reel 15, not digitized ( ARS0035_15_Reel_NOT_Transferred.txt ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 text file (Audio 2, Reel 15)
      Noise, not digitized.
      Audiotape, Digital .txt text file
    - Reel 16, not digitized ( ARS0035_16_Reel_NOT_Transferred.txt ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 text file (Audio 3, Reel 16)
      Blank, not digitized
    - Reel 17, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_17.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 2, Reel 17)
      Hammond organ doodling, play reading; Bing Crosby "Story of Sorrento" (end); Bing Crosby with Rhythmaires "C'mon Along and Shoot the Breeze" or "Flying W" ?; "Big Brass Band from Brazil" (take 2, too high vocal, incomplete)
    - Reel 18, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_18.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 2, Reel 18)
      Ramona Lewis voice tests (probably from disc); aerodynamics dialogue
    - Reel 19, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_19.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 3, Reel 19)
      very short miscellaneous pieces; standup comedian; Bing Crosby Minute Maid commercial and announcements to be used on the air
    - Reel 20, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_20.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 3, Reel 20)
      ski clothes fashion show at Sun Valley; Bill Palmer talking about movies and television; Palmer, a woman, and team packing up equipment; section in reverse: Roos Brothers commercial; Bing Crosby "Blue of the Night"; "160 acres"
    - Reel 21, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_21.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 3, Reel 21)
      Sun Valley ski promotional piece
    - Reel 22, not digitized ( ARS0035_22_Reel_NOT_Transferred.txt ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 text file (Audio 3, Reel 22)
      traffic safety PSA; logging promotion; Del Monte pineapple ad. Not digitized.
    - Reel 23, partially digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_23_Crosby_portion.wav ); ( ARS0035_23_Reel_MOST_NOT_Transferred.txt ), 1 12" open reel tape, 2 digital files (Audio 3, Reel 23)
      judging beef cattle: the Junior Grand National at the Cow Palace. Near the end, Bing Crosby sings "Peg-o-My-Heart." ONLY "Peg-o-My-Heart" was transferred.
      Audiotape, Digital .wav audio file, Digital .txt text file
    - Reel 24, not digitized ( ARS0035_24_Reel_NOT_Transferred.txt ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 text file (Audio 3, Reel 24)
      medical talk for about two minutes near the start, most of tape is blank. not digitized.
    - Reel 25, not digitized ( ARS0035_25_Reel_NOT_Transferred.txt ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 text file (Audio 3, Reel 25)
      untransferrable; "dark brown oxide, stiff, cupped"
    - Reel 26, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_26.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 3, Reel 26)
      R-rated story teller; attacking Florence, Italy; "This is number 10, 9... " etc.; Bill Palmer singers - production song; scissors sharpener commercial
    - Reel 27, not digitized ( ARS0035_27_Reel_NOT_Transferred.txt ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 text file (Audio 3, Reel 27)
      medical presentation for entire length, not digitized.
    - Reel 28, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_28.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 2, Reel 28)
      political speech excerpts re: taxation outtakes; two little boys fable (re: sports) with music introduction
    - Reel 29, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_29.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 2, Reel 29)
      concrete instructional film soundtrack; miscellaneous film excerpts; music snippets; "O Susanna"; "California Here I Come"; "San Francisco"
    - Reel 30, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_30.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 2, Reel 30)
      Bing Crosby snippets; St. Patrick's Day closure announcement (prob. outtake); sound effects
    - Reel 31, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_31.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 31)
      kazoo, bells, misc.; "Good King Wenceslas"; "Jack you ought to provide me with the right instruments, like a good harmonica"; High Fidelity CSTM? with accent?; McCann Ericson copy reading; portion of Mallotte?; setting of The Lord's Prayer (choir); segue to "O Come All Ye Faithful" (hummed); segue to "Ode to Joy" (Beethoven); orchestral, backwards piece
    - Reel 32, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_32.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 32)
      film narration; "For every action there is an equal and opposite reaction"
    - Reel 33, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_33.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 33)
      orchestral music
    - Reel 34, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_34.wav ); ( ARS0035_34_Edited.wav ); ( ARS0035_34_Edited.EDL ), 1947-12-24; 1 10.5" open reel tape, 3 digital files (Audio 1, Reel 34)
      Christmas Eve 1947; "White Christmas"; Charles Taswell's Christmas play "The Small One"; "Silent Night." Edited file also available.
      Audiotape, Two digital .wav audio files, Digital .edl text file
    - Reel 35, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_35.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 35)
      hot water from the beginning of time; bronze (glitches...is this a dub from optical?); Automatic Electric Water Heater; Pacific Gas and Electric wage increase discussions; power shortage of 1947; Utility Worker's Union of America; The American Broadcasting Company sponsor; KGO; SFO
    - Reel 36, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_36.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 36)
      "Story of Sorrento" beginning; Oscar Levant; Peggy Lee "The Man I Love." "Spliced tape to use" on paper sleeve
    - Reel 37, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_37.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 37)
      orchestral excerpts. "MGM Hammond Organ" on hub label
    - Reel 38, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_38.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 38)
      Del Monte pineapples specialized machine soundtrack
    - Reel 39, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_39.wav ), 1949; 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 39)
      toy songs snippets; plum harvest then grapes; migrant workers; strike; "The Di Giorgio Story" 1949
    - Reel 40, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_40.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 40)
      announcement snippets; "return of competitive selling" beeps (filmstrip?); motivational talk, sales. "Rerro [Remo?] Phono" on sleeve
    - Reel 41, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_41.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 2, Reel 41)
      Sonoran Desert; says "Cut, Bill" (so is the narrator Bill Palmer?); horse dialogue; a few snippets, mostly silence; classical music; kid baseball through window dialogue. "Pop mus off air" written on sleeve (not found), "Captain Williams Birds" label on hub
    - Reel 42, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_42.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 42)
      probable outtakes; [aircraft?] engine starting and takeoff; Bing Crosby and Peggy Lee "Dearly Beloved" and "White Christmas" (take 2); Peggy Lee and Bing Crosby "Catalog Day"; "Dearly Beloved" and "White Christmas." "Instruments of the Orchestra" written on sleeve
    - Reel 43, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_43.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 2, Reel 43)
      one minute of tape noise, otherwise blank
    - Reel 44A, digitized with 44B 2003 ( ARS0035_44.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 44A)
      Wilbur Ellis Company soundtrack; tour of Peru; bonito versus tuna fish. Edited to include 44B
    - Reel 44B digitized with 44A 2003 ( ARS0035_44.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 44B)
      Wilbur Ellis Company soundtrack; tour of Peru; bonito versus tuna fish. Edited to include 44A
    - Reel 45, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_45.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 45)
      film soundtrack snippets: dysentery in small animals; Jerry Colonna "You Haven't Changed At All"; "Call for Philip Morris"; snippets
    - Reel 46, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_46.wav ); ( ARS0035_46_and_63.wav ); ( ARS0035_46_and_63.EDL ), 1948; 1 10.5" open reel tape, 3 digital files (Audio 1, Reel 46)
      Burl Ives; South African singers Josef Marais and Miranda 1948; "Jimmy Crack Corn" (theme); "Sweet Betsy from Pike"; quartet "How A Rose is Blooming." Edited file appending Reel 63 also available.
    - Reel 47, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_47.wav ), 1 12" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 2, Reel 47)
      asking Jack to be quiet; "make your colors sing"; woman producer-director; announcer is Stu; Pine Tour. "Kray Dialogue" on envelope label
    - Reel 48, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_48.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 48)
      Cresta Blanca Wine Chef's Club with host Dean Jennings - intro only; "Union must give a complete account"; "Non-communist affidavit for employers also"; Fifth District Congressional race; Y.J. Cosgrove not depicted as a puppet; Tuesday November eighth
    - Reel 49, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_49.wav ), 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 49)
      classical music and other snippets; skiing, winter vacation Sun Valley etc.; Chapter nine; sorting and opening mail; pamphlet on skiing
    - Reel 50, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_50.wav ), 1950; 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 50)
      lip synch Gray-Wilcox tape recorder; Acme Beer promotional plans 1950 beeps (filmstrip?); Operation "Do it"; Acme Hot Time radio show; Peggy Lee for Acme "Let's Do It"
    - Reel 51, digitized 2003 ( ARS0035_51.wav ), 1950; 1 10.5" open reel tape, 1 sound file (Audio 1, Reel 51)
      Bing Crosby and unknown with piano "La Vie en Rose" in French; "Blue of the Night"; "Someone Waits for Me"; Claudette Colbert announced later; "Thousand Island Song"; "Yodel Song" (incomplete); welcome to Claudette Colbert; 1955 in the future; Acme Beer 1950
  - Tape Segments
    - Segments 14-16, 18-23, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2, Box 1, Reel 1)
    - Segment 17, 1948-02; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2, Box 2, Reel 1)
      Assembled with and transferred as part of February 1948 Bing Crosby Show recording, aka "Audiotape_Hubless_Crosby_Show_Assembled"
  - German tape parts and packaging, circa 1943; 2 boxes (Box 5, Box 6)
- Series 2. Eve Mullin Collier, 31 sound files
  Source of Original Tapes
  Tapes in this series borrowed, transferred, and returned to Jack Mullin's daughter, Eve Mullin Collier in 2008.
  - Reels 52-63
    - Reel 52, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_52.wav ), 1948-02-04; 1 sound file
      Demonstration tape found on Magnetophon at time of Mr. Mullin's death in June 1999: Lutz Templin "Hot Love" announced in German; Bing Crosby and Burl Ives "Cross the Wide Missouri"; Chesterfield commercial; "Too Late Now" (with outtakes); Burl Ives and Cache County Boys in San Francisco; Chesterfield ad; "Only One"; Jimmy Durante with Bing Crosby Feb. 4, 1948; Lutz Templin "When Lights are Low"
      Digital .wav audio file
    - Reel 53, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_53.wav ), 1 sound file
      Jack Mullin's Magnetophon Demo Tape 1 (for machine A? from ETs?) "It Ain't Fair" Bing Crosby; "I Hadn't Anyone" Ella Fitzgerald; "Rosie" Al Jolson and Bing Crosby; "Georgia" Pearl Bailey; "With My Eyes Wide Open" Bing Crosby; "The Night We Were Young"; Bing Crosby; "Yodel Blues" Bing Crosby; "City Billy Song" Fred Allen; "Wonderful Guy" Mary Martin (portion)
    - Reel 54, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_54.wav ), 1947; 1 sound file
      Magnetophon tape - this is the only reel that contains an original excerpt from a Crosby show recorded in 1947: Jimmy Durante segment; "Dear Old Donegal" (excerpt); "One Saturday Night" Dinah Shore?; "Galway Bay" Bing Crosby; "Oh I Want To Go Back to that Tumbledown Shack Where the Wild Roses Bloom Around the Door" Bing Crosby; Prince Charming dialogue, multiple takes; "Where the Blue of the Night, A Shamrock Waits For Me"; rest is Lutz Templin Orch from Germany (believed to be a copy, quality so-so)
    - Reel 55, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_55.wav ), 1 sound file
      "On Top Of Old Smokey" Bing Crosby and Burl Ives; "May The Good Lord Bless and Keep You" Bing Crosby; "Listen My Loved Ones" Bing Crosby; "Some Enchanted Evening" Bing Crosby; "My Happiness" Ella Fitzgerald; "Mamselle" Bing Crosby; "Someday You'll Want Me" Mills Brothers
    - Reel 56, not digitized ( ARS0035_56_Reel_NOT_Transferred.txt ), 1 text file
      blank, not digitized
      Digital .txt text file
    - Reel 57, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_57.wav ), 1 sound file
      Magnetophon demo tape #5 Copy from 15: Ampex excerpts (EQ haywire) "In the Heart of a Fool"; "You're So Glamorous" Bing Crosby; "On Top of Old Smokey" Burl Ives; "Old Chisholm Trail"; "Tennessee Waltz" Bing Crosby; "Mona Lisa" Nat King Cole; "Qui Sas, Qui Sas, Qui Sas" Bing Crosby; "Oceana Roll" unidentified female vocal; "Would I Love You" Peggy Lee; "Love is Funny"; "Autumn Leaves" Bing Crosby
    - Reel 58, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_58.wav ), 1 sound file
      Jack Mullin's Magnetophon demo modern copy
    - Reel 59, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_59.wav ), 1 sound file
      Khachaturian's Masquerade Suite
    - Reel 60, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_60.wav ), 1 sound file
      Crosby Show selections: "Autumn Leaves"; "Beyond the Reef"; "Simple Melody" ("first recording I did at Crosby house at Hayden Lake, Idaho on first Ampex Model 300 out of factory" but someone else wrote: "Not true, this recording done before audience" (original on a different reel); "Dear Heart" Gary Crosby; "Fire House Stomp" Fire House Five; "Yes Sir, That's My Baby" Fire House Five and Bing Crosby; "Red River Valley" Fire House Five; "My Baby Don't Love" Fire House Five and Bing Crosby
    - Reel 61, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_61.wav ), 1934-1936; 1 sound file
      test tones 1934-1936
    - Reel 62, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_62.wav ), 1947-12; 1 sound file
      Burl Ives, Dick Davis and his Quartette Christmas 1947 Special
    - Reel 63, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_63.wav ); ( ARS0035_46_and_63.wav ); ( ARS0035_46_and_63.EDL ), 1947-12; 3 digital files
      Philco Show Dec. 1947 with Burl Ives, Josef Marais and Miranda. Edited file with Reel 46 appended also available.
      Two digital .wav audio files, Digital .edl text file
  - Reels 68-87
    - Reel 68, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_68_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      Bing Crosby at fundraiser, Sunset Memorial Centre, Vancouver, BC. "Ballerina" (John Scott Trotter); distorted orchestra music with level variations; more Bing Crosby "Glow worm"; "Thanks for the Memory" with Bob Taylor
    - Reel 69, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_69_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      Bing Crosby and Oscar Levant, Peggy Lee, Gershwin songs: "They Can't Take That Away From Me"; "I Got Rhythm"; "Summertime"
    - Reel 70, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_70_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      Bing Crosby rehearsals. "Love Me Or Leave Me"; "Wolf Creek Pass" (Jimmy Stewart); "But Beautiful" from Road to Rio; "Idaho"; "Where the Blue of the Night Meets the Gold of the Day"; "Love Me Or Leave Me"; "Lili Bolero" Margaret O'Brien "160 Acres"
    - Reel 71, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_71_01_M24.wav ), 1948-03; 1 sound file